Finding Aid for the Slee Lecture Recital Recordings, 1957-1975
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Slee Lecture Recital Recordings, 1957-1975
Mus. Arc. 62
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Department
94 reel to reel tapes ( 15 linear feet )
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection of Slee Lecture Recital Recordings contains 94 reel to reel tapes of lectures by the named Slee Visiting Lecturer in the Music Department at the State University of New York at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access and Use
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Music Department, State University of New York at Buffalo.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
The reel to reel tapes were reformatted to cassettes sometime in the 1970s or 1980s. It is possible that when these transfers were made, they were done in such a way that any musical works presented within a lecture were separated out to stand on their own rather than transferring the entire lecture-recital in its original presentation order. The cassettes have been retained for this reason.
The reels of tape were also digitally reformatted. The preservation files were stored on a hard drive and CD audio discs were created as service copies. However, on the service copies there may not be a one-to-one correspondence between musical works or lectures to discrete tracks or audio files.
Historical Note
Frederick Caldecott Slee was born 25 September 1870 in Skaneatles, New York. He studied music at Harvard while earning his undergraduate degree there. He was a violist and a composer of more than three dozen works. His wife Alice and he bequeathed funds to the University of Buffalo to establish an annual concert series at the University of the entire cycle of Beethoven's string quartets, an ongoing musical tradition in Buffalo. They also designated funds to be used to pay renowned composers or music theorists to come to the University as the Slee Visiting Professor in Music. The chief component of the teaching obligation was to present public lecture recitals, the topics and programs of which were to be determined by the visiting professor. The resulting Slee Lecture Recitals took place 1957-1975. The fund was later shifted to be used for a Slee Chair position in music theory within the department rather than funding visiting faculty.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Slee Lecture Recital Recordings contains 94 reel to reel tapes of lectures by the named Slee Visiting Lecturer in the Music Department at the State University of New York at Buffalo. There were 76 lecture-recitals presented and approximately 277 works programmed. Unfortunately, not all programs or works were recorded.
Lecturers included Aaron Copland, Leon Kirchner, Carlos Chavez, Ned Rorem, David Diamond, Allen Sapp, Haieff, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, George Rochberg, Mauricio Kagel, Luciano Berio, Daniel Pinkham, Henri Pousseur, Lejaren Hiller, Istvan Anhalt, Nicholas Nabokov, Morton Feldman, Luis De Pablo, Harrison Birtwistle, and Betsy Jolas.
Arrangement
The collection is chronologically arranged by event.
Container List
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 1, October 10, 1957, 1957-10-10, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_001_01.wav, ubmu0062_001_02.wav, ubmu0062_001_03.wav (Box 1, Reel 002 Side 1, 003 Side 1)
  Work number: ubmu0062_001_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 001
  Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990
  Lecture: Introduction to the contemporary idiom
  Performers: Aaron Copland, lecturer
  Duration: 30:00
  Note: Side 1 only on both reels; Side 2 of each contains Lecture 2. Titles from printed program.
  Work number: ubmu0062_001_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 002
  Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918
  Preludes. Book II, No. 2, 12
  Performers: Allen Giles, piano
  Duration: 6:48
  Note: Side 1 only; Side 2 contains recital music for Lecture 2. The individual titles of works are taken from a printed program not the container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_001_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 003
  Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945
  Bagatelles, op. 6. no. 13, 1
  Performers: Livingston Gearhart, piano
  Duration: 2:51
  Work number: ubmu0062_001_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 004
  Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
  Five easy pieces
  Performers: Livingston Gearhart, Carol Wolf, pianos
  Duration: 5:08
  Work number: ubmu0062_001_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 005
  Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
  Pierrot Lunaire, op. 21. No. 1, 4, 7, 9
  Performers: Dorothy Rosenberger, soprano; Robert Mols, flute; Allen Sigel, clarinet; Harry Taub, violin; Dorris Jane Dugan-Baird, violoncello; Cameron Baird, piano
  Duration: 6:25
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 2, November 14, 1957, 1957-11-14, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_002_01.wav, ubmu0062_002_02.wav, ubmu0062_002_03.wav (Box 1, Reel 001 Side 2, 003 Side 2)
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 006
  Lecture: Music of the twenties
  Note: Side 2 only; Side 1 contains Lecture 1, Part 1
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 011
  Berg, Alban, 1885-1935
  Vier Stucke fur Klarinette und Klavier, op. 5
  Performers: Allen Sigel, clarinet; Squire Haskin, piano
  Duration: 6:01
  Note: Side 2 only; Side 1 contains recital music for Lecture 1. The individual titles of works are taken from a printed program not the container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 010
  Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
  Marienleben, 1948. 1, 5, 11, 15
  Performers: Dorothy Rosenberger, soprano; Squire Haskin, piano
  Duration: 10:12
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 009
  Suite italienne. Introduzione, Gavotta, Finale
  Performers: Pamela Gearhart, violin; Livingston Gearhart, piano
  Duration: 6:55
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 007
  Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974
  Rape of Europa
  Performers: Dorothy Rosenberger, Deok X. Koe, Vehan Khanzadian, Richard Siegel, principal roles; Unnamed chorus and orchestra; David G. Gooding, conductor
  Duration: 2:39
  Note: Only first part of opera recorded. Side 2 only; Side 1 contains recital music for Lecture 1. The individual titles of works are taken from a printed program not the container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_002_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 008
  Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963
  Bestiaire
  Performers: Toni Packer, alto; David G. Gooding, piano
  Duration: 4:25
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 3, December 5, 1957, 1957-12-05, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_003_01.wav, ubmu0062_003_02.wav, ubmu0062_003_03.wav (Box 1, Reel 004 Side 1, 005 Side 1)
  Work number: ubmu0062_003_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 012
  Lecture: Current trends in European music
  Note: Side 1 only; Side 2 contains Lecture 4 part 2
  Work number: ubmu0062_003_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 013
  Webern, Anton, 1883-1945
  Variationen fur Klavier, op. 27
  Duration: 6:12
  Note: Side 1 only; Side 2 contains recital music for Lecture 4. The individual titles of works are taken from a printed program not the container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_003_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 014
  Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976
  Seven sonnets of Michelangelo, op. 22. No. 1, 3, 5, 7
  Performers: Stanley Wieczorek, tenor; Squire Haskin, piano
  Duration: 10:44
  Work number: ubmu0062_003_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 015
  Henze, Hans Werner, 1926-
  Quintet, woodwinds. 1 (fragment), 3
  Performers: UB Woodwind Quintet: Robert Mols, flute; De Vere Moore, oboe; Allen Sigel, clarinet; Robert Hughes, bassoon; Lowell Shaw, horn
  Duration: 4:42
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 4, January 16, 1958, 1958-01-16, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_004_01.wav, ubmu0062_004_02.wav, ubmu0062_004_03.wav (Box 1, Reel 004 Side 2, 006 Side 2)
  Work number: ubmu0062_004_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 018
  Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999
  Sayula
  Duration: 0:52
  Note: Side 2 only; Side 1 contains recital music for Lecture 3. The individual titles of works are taken from a printed program not the container.
  Original cassette number: SLR 019
  Ives, Charles, 1874-1954
  Three songs: At the river, Serenity, Charlie Rutlage
  Performers: Herbert Beattie, bass; Livingston Gearhart, piano
  Duration: 5:37
  Work number: ubmu0062_004_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 020
  Fine, Irving, 1914-1962
  Partita. I, III, IV
  Performers: U.B. Woodwind Quintet: Robert Mols, flute; De Vere Moore, oboe; Allen Sigel, clarinet; Hughes, bassoon; Lowell Shaw, horn
  Duration: 8:39
  Work number: ubmu0062_004_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 016
  Lecture: The American composer today
  Duration: 25:00
  Note: Side 2 only; Side 1 contains Lecture 3 part 2
  Work number: ubmu0062_004_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 021
  12 poems of Emily Dickinson (1949-50). 1, 7, 11, 12
  Performers: Ruth Johnson Mohn, soprano; Aaron Copland, piano
  Duration: 12:30
  Work number: ubmu0062_004_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 017
  Diamond, David, 1915-2005
  Concerto, pianos 2 (1942)
  Duration: 3:57
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 5, March 6, 1958, 1958-03-06, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_005_01.wav, ubmu0062_005_02.wav (Box 1, Reel 007)
  Work number: ubmu0062_005_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 022
  Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978
  Lecture: Introduction to Latin American music
  Performers: Carlos Chávez, lecturer
  Note: Audio quality is marred by loud coughing directly into the microphone.
  Work number: ubmu0062_005_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 023
  Plaza, Juan Bautista, 1898-1965
  Fuga romantica venezolana (1950)
  Performers: Unnamed string orchestra; Carlos Chavez, conductor
  Duration: 5:18
  Note: Titles of performed works from cassette catalog, not from original reel container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_005_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 024
  Fuga criolla (1931)
  Duration: 4:44
  Work number: ubmu0062_005_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 025
  Halffler, Rodolf
  Tres piezas (1954)
  Duration: 11:55
  Work number: ubmu0062_005_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 026
  Tosar Errecart, Héctor A. (Héctor Alberto), 1923-
  Symphony no. 2
  Duration: 24:43
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 6, April 17, 1958, 1958-04-17, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_006_01.wav, ubmu0062_006_02.wav (Box 1, Reel 008)
  Work number: ubmu0062_006_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 029
  Caamaño, Roberto, 1923-
  Music for strings
  Duration: 17:07
  Work number: ubmu0062_006_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 030
  Sinfonia, string orchestra, no. 5
  Duration: 21:27
  Work number: ubmu0062_006_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 028
  Galindo, Blas, 1910-1993
  Sinfonia breve (1956)
  Duration: 17:50
  Work number: ubmu0062_006_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 027
  Lecture: Latin American music
  Duration: 40:00
  Note: There is some bad interference on the tape towards the middle of the lecture.
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 8, May 29, 1958, 1958-05-29, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_008_01.wav, ubmu0062_008_02.wav (Box 1, Reel 009)
  Work number: ubmu0062_008_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 035
  Lecture: Untitled
  Note: The first part of the cassette tape is unusable due to hum. It sounds as if this is part of the original recording set-up and so returning to the original tape probably won't provide a solution.
  Work number: ubmu0062_008_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 036
  Soli I (1933)
  Performers: Ronald Richards, oboe; James Pyne, clarinet; Frank Collura, trumpet; Robert Hughes, bassoon
  Duration: 6:46
  Work number: ubmu0062_008_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 037
  Tree of sorrow (1942)
  Performers: Unknown chorus
  Duration: 2:04
  Work number: ubmu0062_008_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 038
  Three nocturnes
  Duration: 4:40
  Work number: ubmu0062_008_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 039
  Three songs (?)
  Performers: Performer(s) unknown
  Duration: 12:46
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 9, March 23, 1959, 1959-03-23, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_009.wav (Box 1, Reel 010 Side 1)
  Work number: ubmu0062_009_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 040
  Kirchner, Leon
  Lecture: Materials of musical composition
  Performers: Leon Kirchner, lecturer; Pamela Gearhart, violin; Livingston Gearhart, piano; Herbert Beattie, bass baritone; Janice Menel, Joyce Ismert, Ann Holblinger, Elaine Merritt, Elizabeth Winkler, Dorcas DeMunn, voices
  Note: Side 1 only: Side 2 is marked "Reading of an Ibsen play"
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 12, May 22, 1959, 1959-05-22, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_012.wav (Box 1, Reel 012)
  Work number: ubmu0062_012_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 053
  Trio, piano, violin, violoncello
  Performers: Theodora Mantz, violin; Donald McCall, violoncello; Leon Kirchner, piano
  Duration: 13:53
  Work number: ubmu0062_012_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 051
  Stilman, Julia, 1935-
  Quarteto
  Performers: John Rowland, xylophone; Frank Collura, trumpet; James Pyne, clarinet; Donald McCall, violoncello
  Duration: 6:16
  Note: Composer stated as Ada Julia Stilman de Lasansky in cassette catalog
  Work number: ubmu0062_012_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 050
  Hauschka, Elsa
  Two songs to Blake poems
  Performers: Dorothy Rosenberger, soprano; Robert Mols, flute; Lowell Shaw, horn; Donald Shrimpton, piano
  Duration: 10:27
  Note: Second song repeated after applause
  Work number: ubmu0062_012_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 049
  Seitz, Kenneth
  Scherzo
  Performers: Donald Shrimpton, piano
  Duration: 3:58/3:51
  Note: Repeated after applause
  Work number: ubmu0062_012_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 048
  Performers: Leon Kirchner, lecturer
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 13, December 3, 1959, 1959-12-03, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_013_01.wav, ubmu0062_013_02.wav (Box 2, Reel 013)
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_12
  Original cassette number: SLR 065
  Rorem, Ned, 1923-
  Youth, day, old age, and night
  Performers: Regipa Sarfaty, mezzo-soprano; Ned Rorem, piano
  Duration: 2:00
  Note: Title of work from cassette catalog, not from original container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_10
  Original cassette number: SLR 063
  Sally's smile
  Duration: 0:39
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_18
  Original cassette number: SLR 071
  I am Rose
  Duration: 0:12
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_17
  Original cassette number: SLR 070
  Early in the morning
  Duration: 1:33
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_16
  Original cassette number: SLR 069
  Spring and fall
  Duration: 2:01
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_15
  Original cassette number: SLR 068
  What if some little pain
  Duration: 1:45
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_13
  Original cassette number: SLR 066
  To you
  Duration: 0:28
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_11
  Original cassette number: SLR 064
  O you whom I often and silently come
  Duration: 0:21
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_19
  Original cassette number: SLR 072
  Alleluia
  Duration: 2:15
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_08
  Original cassette number: SLR 061
  Rain in spring
  Duration: 1:18
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_07
  Original cassette number: SLR 060
  Midnight sun
  Duration: 1:37
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 059
  Oedipus Rex. Nonn' erubeskite, reges
  Duration: 5:58
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 058
  Chanler, Theodore, 1902-1961
  Two songs: Ann Poverty; Be very quiet now
  Duration: 1:42
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 057
  Flanagan, William, 1923-1969
  Two songs: Send home my long strayed eyes; [Unknown song]
  Duration: 3:45
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 056
  Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989
  Two songs
  Duration: 2:44
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 055
  Twelve poems of Emily Dickinson. 3, 11
  Duration: 4:38
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 054
  Performers: Ned Rorem, lecturer
  Note: Very poor sound quality on cassette transfer
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_14
  Original cassette number: SLR 067
  Visits to St. Elizabeths
  Duration: 3:20
  Work number: ubmu0062_013_09
  Original cassette number: SLR 062
  Lordly Hudson
  Duration: 2:24
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 14, January 26, 1960, 1960-01-26, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_014_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_014_01_02.wav, ubmu0062_014_02_01.wav (Box 2, Reel 014-015)
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 075
  Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965
  Andante con moto
  Performers: Robert Brink, violin; Daniel Pinkham, harpsichord
  Duration: 2:41
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_07
  Original cassette number: SLR 079
  Pinkham, Daniel
  Cantilena and capriccio
  Duration: 6:14
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 078
  Bavicchi, John, 1922-
  Short sonata
  Duration: 6:22
  Note: Written for this program; Premiere performance. Title of work from cassette catalog, not from original container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 076
  Hovhaness, Alan, 1911-2000
  Duet for violin and harpsichord
  Duration: 2:31/2:32
  Note: Title of work from cassette catalog, not from original container. Played again as an encore
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 074
  Henning, Ervin, 1910-1982
  Fantasia for violin and harpsichord
  Duration: 6:21
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 073
  Lecture: Four questions answered
  Work number: ubmu0062_014_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 077
  Ray, Mans George
  Trialogue
  Duration: 2:19
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 15, February 25, 1960, 1960-02-25, 2 7 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_015_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_015_01_02.wav, ubmu0062_015_02_01.wav, ubmu0062_015_02_02.wav (Box 2, Reel 016-017)
  Work number: ubmu0062_015_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 080
  Lecture: Writing songs
  Work number: ubmu0062_015_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 081
  Satie, Erik, 1866-1925
  Socrate (1919). The death of Socrates
  Performers: Dorothy Rosenberger, soprano; Patricia Oreskovic, mezzo-soprano; Ned Rorem, piano
  Duration: 17:10
  Note: Title of work from cassette catalog, not from original container. Buffalo premiere
  Work number: ubmu0062_015_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 082
  Sonata, pianos 2 (1945)
  Performers: Allen Giles, Ned Rorem, pianos
  Duration: 9:41
  Work number: ubmu0062_015_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 083
  Sicilienne for two pianos (1950)
  Duration: 3:14
  Work number: ubmu0062_015_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 084
  Canticle no. 2 (Abraham and Isaac) (1952)
  Performers: Stanley Curtis, tenor; Patricia Oreskovic, mezzo-soprano; Ned Rorem, piano
  Duration: 15:12
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 17, May 17, 1960, 1960-05-17, 1 7 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_017.wav (Box 2, Reel 018)
  Work number: ubmu0062_017_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 093
  Lecture: Listening and hearing
  Note: Container only indicates Eleven studies but the cassette catalog indicates this lecture was recorded
  Work number: ubmu0062_017_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 094
  Eleven studies for eleven players
  Performers: Robert Mols, flute, piccolo; Ronald Richards, oboe, English horn; Allen Sigel, clarinet; Frank Collura, trumpet; George D'Anna, John Rowland, percussion; Marjorie Winey, harp; Allen Giles, piano; Pamela Gearhart, violin; Fred Ressel, viola; Alta Mayer, vi
  Duration: Less than 30 minutes
  Note: Premiere performance
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 25, November 30, 1961, 1961-11-30, 1 10 inch reel; Butler Auditorium, Capen Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_025.wav (Box 2, Reel 019)
  Work number: ubmu0062_025_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 124
  Sapp, Allen, 1922-1000
  Lecture: The lyric impulse
  Performers: Allen Sapp, lecturer
  Work number: ubmu0062_025_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 125
  Fetes galantes
  Performers: Jennie Tourel, mezzo-soprano; James Wadsworth, piano
  Note: Marked as Not recorded in cassette catalog but original should be checked for its presence
  Work number: ubmu0062_025_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 126
  Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881
  Songs and dances of death
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 26, February 5, 1962, 1962-02-05, 1 7 inch reel; Butler Auditorium, Capen Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_026_01.wav, ubmu0062_026_02.wav (Box 2, Reel 020)
  Work number: ubmu0062_026_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 127
  Lecture: The corporate experience
  Note: Cassette catalog marked Tape incomplete. Reel container marked "Tracks superimposed at about 3:25"
  Work number: ubmu0062_026_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 128
  Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937
  Trio, violin, viola, violoncello, op. 58 (1937)
  Performers: Joseph Silverstein, violin; Joseph de Pasquale, viola; Samuel Mayers, violoncello
  Note: Cassette catalog indicates it was Not recorded but it is marked on the reel container - check for content
  Work number: ubmu0062_026_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 129
  Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
  Trio, violin, viola, violoncello, op. 9, no. 3, C minor
  Work number: ubmu0062_026_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 130
  Trio, violin, viola, violoncello (1956) G
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 40, February 14, 1964, 1964-02-14, 1 5 inch reel; Butler Auditorium, Capen Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_040.wav (Box 2, Reel 021)
  Work number: ubmu0062_040_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 224
  Rochberg, George
  Lecture: The new image of music
  Performers: George Rochberg, lecturer
  Note: Container marked "Dub of Rochberg; excerpts from lectures 1 and 2" - check for content for Lecture 1 which is otherwise marked as tape lacking in the cassette catalog
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 41, March 20, 1964, 1964-03-20, 1 7 inch reel; Butler Auditorium, Capen Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_041.wav (Box 2, Reel 022)
  Work number: ubmu0062_041_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 227
  Lecture: Direction in Music
  Note: Recording of Rochberg lecture 2; 3/20/64? [end missing] "L. Ch. Only". Check Reel 21 to see if any content there is missing from Reel 22. Also check Reel 22b which is marked Dub with complete ending. Choose most complete copy.
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 42, April 16, 1964, 1964-04-16, 2 7 inch reels; Butler Auditorium, Capen Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_042_01.wav, ubmu0062_042_02.wav (Box 2, Reel 023-024)
  Work number: ubmu0062_042_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 232
  Quartet, strings, no. 2 with soprano (1961)
  Performers: Janice Harsany, soprano; Veda Reynolds, Alan Iglitzin, violins; Irwin Eisenberg, viola; Charles Brennand, violoncello
  Duration: 12:19
  Note: Containers do not contain specific program contents so the piece could be on either Reel 23 or Reel 24. Cassette catalog is marked "End of piece missing (not recorded?) "
  Work number: ubmu0062_042_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 230
  Lecture: The computer, the brain and music
  Note: Possibly continued on Reel 24
  Work number: ubmu0062_042_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 231
  Quartet, strings, no. 1, 1952
  Performers: Veda Reynolds, Alan Iglitzin, violins; Irwin Eisenberg, viola; Charles Brennand, violoncello
  Duration: 24:41
  Note: Containers do not contain specific program contents so the piece could be on either Reel 23 or Reel 24